翻譯: Cyber願你永遠穿漂亮衣服
校對: Kyle
後期: Jevic
電波字幕組 歡迎您的加入
官方網站:www.dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@電波字幕組
電波字幕組      誠心誠譯
異     形    3
Fiorina 復仇161星
外圍礦砂提煉場
雙Y染色體勞改監獄
最高安全級別
Fiorina 復仇161C級監獄彩虹女神-12037154
報告 逃生艇2650墜落
一名生還者——
Fiorina 復仇161C級監獄彩虹女神-12037154
報告 逃生艇2650墜落
一名生還者——Ripley中尉
亡者——Hicks下士
亡者——不明身份女性
年齡約10歲
請求迅速救援
等候批示——獄長Andrews
至復仇161C級監獄
通訊衛星01500——收到訊息
嚴禁擠壓
已困住異形怪物
請求批准消滅
至復仇161星 C級監獄
公司收到訊息
救援隊於1200小時後到達
拒絕請求 不允許消滅異形怪物
救援隊抵達前避免接觸異形
拒絕請求
收到逃生艇2650神經掃瞄數據
醫療隊兩小時之內到達
絕對最高優先級
隔離Ripley中尉
絕對最高優先級 隔離Ripley中尉
等待確認
傳訊完畢
靜態平衡中斷 冷凍倉失火
Stasis interrupted. Fire in cryogenic compartment.
重複 冷凍倉失火
Repeat. Fire in cryogenic compartment.
全體船員速到
All personnel report to...
緊急逃生艇集合
emergency escape vehicle.
逃生艇將在
Launch of the escape lifeboat will commence...
20秒之後發射
in T-minus 20 seconds.
一艘逃生艇墜落了
An E.E.V.'s come down.
到沙灘去 可能還有其他人
Get down to the beach. There may be others.
快去
Now!
說話
Talk to me.
快醒醒 醒醒
Come on. Come on.
嘿 Frank 快 快走 快走
Hey, Frank! Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
慢點
Wait!
接著走 Frank 進去
Get goin', Frank. Get in there.
哦 天吶
Oh! Jesus Christ!
這他媽什麼著陸方式
Hell of a way to make a landing!
用手電筒吧
Use the torch.
- 要多少  - 不知道
- How many? - Don't know.
三個吧 或者四個
Three. Maybe four.
嘿 Frank 能快點嗎
Hey, Frank. Can we hurry this up?
5分鐘後就要降到零下40度了
It's gonna be 40 below in five minutes.
好了 好了 開始吧
All right, all right. Let's get it going.
團結一點 快點
Keep it together. Come on. Right.
好了 來吧 Dillon先生
Right. Here we go, Mr. Dillon.
主啊 賜予我們力量來忍受
Give us strength, O Lord, to endure.
我們只是上帝手中
We recognize that we are
卑微的罪人
poor sinners in the hands of an angry God.
但願循環不被破壞
Let the circle be unbroken...
直到末日降臨
until the day.
- 阿門  - 阿門
- Amen. - Amen.
多謝各位 下面開始闢謠
Thank you, gentlemen. This is rumor control.
情況如下
Here are the facts.
你們也知道
As some of you know,
有一艘337型號緊急逃生艇
a 337 model E.E.V....
於早上6點
crash-landed here at 0600...
墜落在我們這兒
on the morning watch.
艇上僅一人生還
There was one survivor,
另外有兩名死者和一個報廢的生化人
two dead and a droid that was hopelessly smashed beyond repair.
生還者為女性
The survivor is a woman.
我所瞭解的就是這樣
That's what I saw.
我已經宣誓要獨身禁慾了
I just want to say that I've taken a vow of celibacy.
- 我們都宣誓了  - 包括女人在內
- So have we all. - That also includes women.
- 是  - 我們已經宣誓了
- Yes. - We've all taken the vow!
- 閉上臭嘴 Morse  - 我還是想說 首先
- Shut your gob, Morse. - I'd like to say that I, for one,
我不喜歡公司允許她在這裏
do not appreciate company policy allowing her to freely...
與囚犯和獄卒混在一起生活
intermingle with inmates and the rest of the staff.
這位兄弟想說的是
What brother means to say
我們認為任何外人出現
is we view the presence of any outsider,
尤其是女人 都會破壞這裏的和諧
especially a woman, as a violation of the harmony,
有可能破壞我們的聖神團體
a potential break in the spiritual unity.
我們很清楚大家的想法
We are well aware of your feelings in this matter.
所以 我已經請求了救援小組到來
You will be pleased to know that I have requested a rescue team.
希望他們一周之內就能趕到
Hopefully, they will be here inside of a week
- 哦 拜託  - 盡快將她帶走
- Oh, come on! - And evacuate her A.S.A.P.
別這樣玩我們
Don't give us that!
她身體狀況如何
What's her medical status?
她傷勢不重
She doesn't seem too badly damaged.
目前昏迷不醒
She's unconscious.
還沒有進一步的詳細診斷
Can't give you a more specific diagnosis at the moment.
- 她能活下來嗎  - 應該可以
- Will she live? - I would think so.
聽著 所有人都不希望
Look. It's in everybody's interest...
那個女人
the woman doesn't come out
在救援小組到達之前從醫務室出來
of the infirmary until the rescue team arrives.
- 更不希望沒人護送 明白嗎  - 是
- And certainly not without an escort, right? - Sir.
各位 我們繼續回到日常狀態
Gentlemen, we should all stick to our set routine...
不要過分焦慮
and not get unduly agitated.
- 是  - 可以嗎
- Right. - Correct?
很好 謝謝各位
All right. Thank you, gentlemen.
好了
All right.
快點去吧 不然就沒多少剩了
Better get here soon or there ain't gonna be much left.
這是什麼
What's that?
我自己調的一點雞尾酒 保證沒見過
It's just a little cocktail of my own mix. Sort of eye-opener.
你是醫生
You a doctor?
我叫Clemens 我是這兒的醫務主管
My name is Clemens. I'm the chief medical officer here.
- 這兒  - 復仇161星
- Here?  - Fury 161.
這是Weyland-Yutani的窮鄉僻壤的苦役監獄
It's one of Weyland-Yutani's backwater work prisons,
說起來就讓我悲傷
it grieves me to say.
不介意吧
Do you mind?
這東西是鎮靜劑
This is basically a stabilizer.
我要把你頭髮給剃了
I really ought to shave your head.
裏面有很多虱子
We have a big problem with lice here.
你感覺好點後 我給你拿個剪刀
And when you're feeling better, I'll give you some clippers,
你自己剪掉你的
and you can tend to your
- 陰毛  - 我怎麼來這兒的
- private parts yourself. - How'd I get here?
你的逃生艇墜落了
You crash-landed in an E.E.V.
明顯是進入大氣層之前
Evidently separated from
就已經脫離母艦了
your mother ship before you hit our atmosphere.
你知道你處於深度休眠多久了嗎
You have any idea how long you were in hypersleep?
你這麼突然甦醒
'Cause coming out the way
肯定會讓身體系統受到影響
you did can be quite a jolt to the system.
- 我會病幾個星期  - 沒錯
- Yeah, I'll be sick for a couple of weeks. - Indeed.
- 其他人呢  - 他們沒能生還
- Where are the others? - They didn't make it.
- 什麼  - 他們都死了
- What? - They didn't survive.
我得去飛船看看
I have to get to the ship.
- 我要去看看  - 你現在的狀況還不能去
- Have to get to the ship. - You're in no condition for that.
你要給我穿點衣服呢 還是就讓我這麼出去
You want to get me some clothes, or should I just go like this?
考慮到本地群眾的性情
Given the nature of our indigenous population,
我建議你穿點衣服
I would suggest clothes.
他們很多年沒見過女人了
None of them have seen a woman in years.
其實 我也不例外
Neither have I, for that matter.
這裏曾關著5000名囚犯
This used to be a 5,000 convict facility,
現在只剩下25名
but it's been reduced to a custodial staff of 25.
為什麼
Why?
- 保持引導燈正常運轉  - 引導燈幹什麼的
- Keep the pilot light on. - The pilot light for what?
高爐鼓風 天然沼氣
Blast furnace. Natural methane.
我們有個鑄造廠 Ripley中尉
We have a foundry, Lieutenant Ripley.
囚犯鑄造鉛板 用來裝有毒廢料
The inmates forge lead sheets for toxic waste containers.
你怎麼知道我的名字
How do you know my name?
印在你短褲背面了
It's stenciled on the back of your shorts.
鬆開鐵纜
Release the cable!
- 屍體在哪兒  - 在停屍房
- Where are the bodies? - We have a morgue.
我們放在那兒了
We put them there until the
等調查小組一周後過來再說
investigative team arrives in about a week, I think.
- 還有個生化人呢  - 斷電了
- There was a droid. - Disconnected.
他七零八碎的
There were bits and pieces of him all over the place.
都丟到垃圾堆頂上了
We put what was left on the rubbish tip.
那個下士被安全架刺穿了
The corporal was impaled by that safety support.
死得不明不白
He never knew what hit him.
那個女孩呢
And the girl?
她 溺死在低溫艙內了
She drowned in her cryo-tube.
我估計她死的時候也沒有甦醒
I don't think she was conscious when it happened.
很抱歉
Um, I'm sorry.
怎麼了
What's the matter?
- 她在哪兒  - 在停屍房
- Where is she? - In the morgue.
我要看看她
I have to see her.
我要看看她的遺體
I have to see what's left of her.
你這麼急迫有什麼理由嗎
Is there any particular reason that you're so insistent?
有 我要確定她的死因
Yes. I have to be sure how she died.
我實在不想囉嗦這個事情了
I hate to be repetitious about such a sensitive subject,
但她確實是溺水而死的
but it is perfectly clear that she drowned.
她是你女兒嗎
Was she your daughter?
不是
No. She wasn't.
讓 讓我獨處一下好嗎
C-Could I have a moment alone, please?
當然可以
Yes, of course.
原諒我
Forgive me.
她在幹嘛
What's she doing?
好了嗎
Okay?
沒有
No.
我們需要驗屍
We have to do an autopsy.
- 什麼  - 我說了
- What? - I told you,
我們得查清楚她的死因
we have to make sure how she died.
我也說過 她是溺死的
And I told you, she drowned.
我認為不是 我要看看她體內
I'm not so sure. I-I have to see inside of her.
你精神恍惚 你一半的身體機能
You're disorientated. Half your system's still in—
我這麼做理由很充分
I have a very, very good reason.
那就請你告訴我
Well, perhaps you'd like to share that reason.
她可能受到感染
Possible contagion.
哪種感染
What kind exactly?
- 霍亂  - 霍亂
- Cholera. - Cholera?
已經有200年沒出現過霍亂病例了
There hasn't been a case of cholera reported for 200 years.
求你了
Please.
一切正常
Everything's in place.
沒有感染跡象
There's no sign of infection.
- 也沒有病癥  - 胸腔呢
- No indication of disease. - Chest.
打開胸腔
Open the chest.
小心
Careful.
肺部
Lungs.
充滿液體
Flooded with fluid.
因此 她是溺死的
Ergo, she drowned.
好了 我不是個傻子
Now, since I'm not a complete idiot,
你能告訴我到底在找什麼嗎
would you like to tell me what we're really looking for?
Clemens先生
Mr. Clemens.
獄長
Superintendent.
你還沒見過Ripley中尉吧
I don't believe you've met Lieutenant Ripley.
Clemens先生 發生什麼了
What's going on, Mr. Clemens?
是的 發生什麼了 Clemens先生
That's right, sir. What's going on, Mr. Clemens？
首先
Well, first—
好消息是 中尉現在狀況好多了
the lieutenant is feeling much better, I'm happy to say.
其次 為了大家的健康考慮
Second, in the interest of public health,
- 我在驗屍  - 未經批准
- I am performing an autopsy. - Without my authority.
來不及向您請示
Well, there didn't seem to be time.
但結果一切無礙
But it's turned out all right.
- 死者體內沒有感染痕跡  - 很好
- There's no sign of contagion in the body. - Good.
而且最好讓Ripley中尉
But it might be helpful if Lt. Ripley
不要在囚犯面前走動
didn't parade around in front of the prisoners,
我聽說她剛剛就這麼做了
as I am told she did in the last hour.
同時 我還認為你應該
It might also be helpful...
及時告訴我她身體狀況的任何變化
if you kept me informed as to any change in her physical status.
這要求過分嗎
Or would that be asking too much?
- 屍體必須火化  - 胡說
- We have to cremate the bodies. - Nonsense.
遺體必須冷凍著 等救援小組來了再說
We'll keep the bodies on ice till the rescue team arrives.
- 冷凍  - 這會影響公眾健康
- On ice. - There is the public health issue.
中尉認為依舊
The lieutenant feels that there
有疾病傳播感染的可能
is still a possibility of a communicable infection.
你不是說沒有疾病跡像嗎
I thought you said there was no sign of disease.
看起來孩子是溺死的
It would appear that the child drowned.
但是未經過化驗室檢測
But without the benefit of proper laboratory tests,
我也不能十分肯定
it's impossible to be absolutely certain.
我認為冒著被感染的可能性
I would consider it unwise to tolerate even
是不太明智的
the possibility of an unwelcome virus.
要是霍亂暴發 您的任職報告一定不會好看
An outbreak of cholera would look extremely bad on a report.
不是嗎 先生
Would it not, sir?
我們有25名囚犯
We've 25 prisoners in this facility.
全是雙Y染色體
All double-y-chromos.
小偷 強姦犯 殺人犯 兒童猥褻犯 全是人渣
All thieves, rapists, murderers, child molesters. All scum.
他們信教
Just because they've taken on religion
並不代表他們不危險
doesn't make them any less dangerous.
我不想挑戰他們的信仰
I try not to offend their convictions.
也不想擾亂這裏的秩序
I don't want to upset the order.
我不想引發風波
I don't want ripples in the water.
我也不想有女人勾起他們的邪念
And I don't want a woman walking around giving them ideas.
懂了 為了我的安全
I see. For my own personal safety.
正是
Exactly.
火化的任務交給你了 Clemens先生
I will leave the details of the cremation to you, Mr. Clemens.
他們可以用熔爐
They may use the furnace,
不過晚上10點以前要回牢房
but I want everyone back in lockup by 2200 hours.
遵命 先生
You called it, sir.
- 聖誕節提早到來了 Murph  - 什麼意思
- Ah, Christmas has come early, Murph. - What do you mean?
- 死了的牛才是好牛  - 太對了
- Any dead ox is a good ox. - You're bloody right.
滿身跳蚤的臭東西
Smelly bastards, all covered in lice.
還剩7只臭東西要處理
There's only seven of the friggin' things left,
然後就完事兒了
and then we're done with them.
最討厭沖洗這臭東西了
God, I hates hosin' these bastards down.
每次弄得我的鞋子上都是屎
I always get shite all over me boots.
- 說到沖洗  - 怎麼了
- Talkin' of hosing things down, Frank  - Yeah?
如果你有機會 你會對她說什麼
You had the chance, what would you say to her?
- 什麼意思 有機會  - 你懂的
- What do you mean, if I got the chance? - You know.
- 如果有機會  - 偶然的
- If you got the chance. - You mean, casual like?
對 你會對她說什麼
Yeah. I mean, how would you put it to her
如果在食堂或者哪裏遇到
if you bumped into her in the mess hall or somewhere?
沒問題
No problem!
我對女人很有辦法的
I've never had any problem with the ladies.
我會說 "親愛的 你好嗎
I'd say to her, "Good day, my dear. How's it goin'?
有什麼可以幫你的嗎"
Anything I can do to be of service?"
然後給她那種眼神 從上看到下
Then I'd give her the look, you know up and down.
然後眨眼睛 色迷迷的笑
And I'd give her the wink, the dirty smile.
- 她就會明白  - 沒錯
- She'd soon get the picture. - Yeah, right.
她就會說 "來親我的屁股吧 老色鬼"
And then she'd say, "Kiss my ass, you horny old fucker!"
我很樂意親她的屁股
I'd be happy to kiss her ass.
親遍她想要的每個地方
I'd be happy to kiss her anywhere she wants.
對 男人不壞 女人不愛
Yeah, but treat 'em mean, keep 'em keen.
- 對吧 Frank  - 跟你說了 Murph
- Right, Frank? - Told you before, Murph.
像婊子一樣操她 像女王一樣寵她
Treat a queen like a whore and a whore like a queen.
錯不了
Can't go wrong.
那女孩怎麼死的
What do you think killed Babe?
鬼知道 反正翹辮子了
Beats me. She just keeled over.
- 她多大了  - 登記的11歲
- How old was she?  - The charts say 1 1 .
正值青春 算了
In her prime. Never mind.
- 等一下就切碎 丟爐裏了  - 對
- We'll chop her up later and throw her in the stew. - Right.
嘿 Frank
Hey，Frank.
這是什麼
What's this?
"我們將這孩子和這男人
"We commit this child...
"托付給您 上帝
"And this man to your keeping, O Lord.
"他們的肉體
"Their bodies...
"已遠離黑暗
"Have been taken from the shadow of our nights.
"他們獲得了解脫
"They have been released...
遠離黑暗與痛苦"
from all darkness and pain."
"這孩子和這男人
"The child and the man...
"已離開我們的世界
"Have gone beyond our world.
"他們已達到永恆
"They are forever eternal...
"永垂不朽
"And everlasting.
塵歸塵 土歸土"
Ashes to ashes, dust to dust."
為什麼
Why?
為何無辜者受到懲罰
Why are the innocent punished?
為何必須犧牲
Why the sacrifice?
為何要有痛苦
Why the pain?
世間原無希望
There aren't any promises.
世事無常
Nothing's certain.
少數能蒙主寵召 得到拯救
Only that some get called, some get saved.
她不會瞭解我們留在人世
She won't ever know the hardship and grief...
必須面對的困苦和傷痛
for those of us left behind.
我們將遺體交託於虛無
We commit these bodies to the void...
並滿心歡喜
with a glad heart.
因為每一顆種子裏
For within each seed,
必將長出花朵
there is a promise of a flower.
每次死亡
And within each death,
無論多麼微不足道
no matter how small,
總伴隨著新生
there's always a new life.
新的開始
A new beginning.
阿門
Amen.
我跟你說 這太他媽奇怪了
I'll tell you, it's fucking weird.
唯一的生還者居然是個女人
The only one to survive that crash is a woman.
她能帶來什麼麻煩
What trouble can she cause?
她帶來了太多改變了
She's already changed everything.
我們他媽能怎麼辦
What the fuck are we supposed to do—
首先
I, for one—
我認真的
I mean it!
好了
Okay.
最近很多流言啊
There's a lot of talking going
說我們不和諧
around that we've got some disharmony here?
可以告訴我是什麼問題嗎
Any you guys want to tell me what the problem is?
說呀 兄弟們
Come on. Speak to me, brothers.
好吧 我說
All right. I'll tell ya.
黑暗無所謂 有蟲子無所謂
I don't mind the dark. I don't mind the bugs.
每周要去一趟那個
I don't mind wanderin' around in some cold,
又濕又冷的隧道也無所謂
wet, damp tunnel for a week at a time.
我一點意見都沒有 但我討厭Golic
I don't mind anything. But I mind Golic.
你也是這麼想的嗎
That the way you feel about it?
對 他瘋瘋癲癲 渾身惡臭
Yeah. The guy's crazy and he smells bad.
我不想和他一起出去了
I ain't going out with him anymore.
你還要說什麼嗎
You got anything to say for yourself?
你們還是得跟他一起
WelI, he's going with you.
Golic就是個可憐的
Golic is just another poor, miserable,
倒霉蛋 跟我們一樣
suffering son of a bitch, just like you and me.
- 除了他很臭  - 還瘋瘋癲癲
- 'Cept he smells worse. - And he's crazy.
給我閉嘴
Knock off the shit!
你們有任務在身
You got a job to do.
我不想再聽到任何有關Golic的事
I don't want to hear another word about Golic.
明白嗎
Okay?
你好啊
Well, hello.
我就知道會這樣 Aaron先生
As I thought, Mr. Aaron.
- 我就知道  - 你說對了
- As I thought. - You called it, sir.
我想感謝一下
I just wanted to, uh, say thanks
你在葬禮上說的話 我
for what you said at the funeral. It was, uh—
我的朋友會很感激的
My friends would have appreciated it.
你不會想認識我的 這位女士
Yeah, well, you don't wanna know me, lady.
我是專殺女人的強姦犯
I'm a murderer and rapist of women.
真的嗎
Really?
我猜我一定讓你很緊張
Well, I guess I must make you nervous.
- 妹子 你有信仰嗎  - 談不上
- Do you have any faith, sister? - Not much.
我們有很深的信仰 甚至足夠讓你加入
Well, we've got a lot of faith here. Enough even for you.
我以為女人不能加入
I thought women weren't allowed.
的確 以前這裏沒有女人
Well, we've never had any before,
但我們包容所有人
but we tolerate anybody.
- 甚至令人無法容忍的人  - 謝謝
- Even the intolerable. - Thank you.
只是說原則 不是針對你
That's just a statement of principle. Nothing personal.
我們一直在這裏好好地等待
You see, we've got a good place to wait here.
以前沒遇到過什麼誘惑
And until now, no temptation.
你們在等什麼
What are you waiting for?
我們在等上帝過來
We're waiting for God to return...
救贖我們這些僕人
and raise his servants to redemption.
Dillon和剩下的奇人異士
Dillon and the rest of the alternative people...
五年前接受了宗教信仰
embraced religion, as it were, about five years ago.
- 擦點碘酒  - 我服藥了
- Tincture? - I'm on medication.
- 不太像  - 哪種宗教
- Hardly. - What kind of religion?
某種啟示論的
Some sort of apocalyptic,
相信千年至福的 基督基礎教派
millenarian, Christian fundamentalist, uh—
- 對  - 正是
- Right. - Exactly.
重點是 公司想關閉監獄
Point is, when the company wanted to close the facility down,
Dillon和其他人希望留下
Dillon and the rest of the converts wanted to stay.
他們獲准以守衛身份留下
And they were allowed to remain as custodians...
加上兩名管理員和
with two minders...
一名醫務主管
and a medical officer.
這就是我們了
And here we are.
你怎麼得到這麼棒的差事的
How did you get this wonderful assignment?
你喜歡這新髮型嗎
How do you like your new haircut?
還行
It's okay.
我為你得罪了Andrews
Now that I've gone out on a limb for you with Andrews,
進一步破壞了
damaged my already
我和那大好人的關係
less-than-perfect relationship with that good man,
也跟你說了
and briefed you...
復仇161星的無聊歷史
on the humdrum history of Fury 161,
你就不能告訴我 你在女孩體內找什麼嗎
can you not tell me what you were looking for in the girl?
你覺得我有吸引力嗎
You attracted to me?
哪方面
In what way?
那方面
In that way.
你很直接
Very direct.
我出門在外很久了
I've been out here a long time.
我也是
So have I.
呃
Yech!
嘿 Spike Spike
Hey, Spike. Spike? Spikey!
你在下面嗎 做什麼呢
Are you down there? What are you doing?
我很感謝你對我的喜愛
I really appreciate your affections,
但我清楚這迴避了我的問題
but I am aware that they... deflected my question.
當然 你的方法很巧妙
In the nicest possible way, of course.
你真掃興
You're spoiling the mood.
我得盡職責
I have a job to do.
我想知道為什麼要焚燒了屍體
I just want to know why we had to cremate the bodies.
現在我在你床上
And now that I'm in your cot,
我就要告訴你答案嗎
you think I owe you an answer.
你是得告訴我理由
I think you owe me an answer.
在不在我床上你都得說
Being in my bed's got nothing to do with it.
我在深睡眠中做了噩夢
I had a terrible dream in hypersleep.
我得知道是什麼害死她
And I had to be sure what killed her.
總之 我錯了
Anyway, I made a mistake.
有可能
Possibly.
現在我又犯了個錯
And now I've made another mistake.
真的 什麼錯
Really? What's that?
和囚犯發展關係
Fraternizing with a prisoner.
肉體接觸 這不合規矩 不是嗎
Physical contact. It's against the rules, isn't it?
當然 幾時發生的
Definitely. When was this?
你應該知道
I think you know.
我又不是囚犯
I'm not a prisoner.
你後腦勺有一個條形碼
You have a bar code on the back of your head.
的確該解釋一下這個
That does deserve an explanation.
但現在不是時候
But I don't think now is the moment.
對不起 我們都挺掃興的 不是嗎
Sorry. We are rather spoiling things, aren't we?
Clemens先生
Mr. Clemens.
- Aaron先生  - 獄長Andrews 要你馬上
- Mr. Aaron. - Superintendent Andrews would like you to report...
到22號通風孔 馬上
to vent shaft 22 on the second quadrant— now.
- 發生意外了  - 嚴重嗎
- We've had an accident. - Something serious?
可以這麼說 有一名囚犯 被切碎了
You could call it that. One of our prisoners has been... diced.
抱歉 得走了
Sorry. I have to go.
職務在身
Official duties.
- 誰死了  - Murphy
- Who was it? - Murphy.
你怎麼知道
How do you know?
那是他的鞋
That's his boot.
我派他來的 他是個傻帽
I gave him the assignment, sir. He was a wanker.
Aaron先生 沒必要道歉 不是你的錯
No apologies, Mr. Aaron. It wasn't your fault.
沒什麼好說的 是吧
Well, not much to say, is there?
- 他當場死亡  - 屁話
- Death was instantaneous. - No shit.
我猜他被吸入風扇了
I take it he was pulled into the fan.
突然的強風 說不定 不過
Sudden rush of air, I'd imagine, except—
對 有次我也差點這樣
Right. Almost happened to me once.
跟他說多少遍了 "離風扇遠點"
I've told him so many times, "Stay away from the fans."
他媽就是沒人聽
Nobody bloody listens.
不過風扇是在吹風
Except the fan was blowing.
- 那是什麼  - 不知道
- What's that? - I don't know.
半小時後 請來我房間
I want to see you in my quarters in 30 minutes,
Clemens先生
if you'll please, Mr. Clemens.
你有什麼推測嗎
Have you got any ideas?
原來你在這兒 這麼一個人到處亂走
Here you are. You know, wandering around without an escort...
會氣死Andrews獄長的
is really gonna piss Superintendent Andrews off.
那意外是怎麼回事
Will you tell me about your accident?
一名囚犯死了
One of the prisoners has been killed.
真的 怎麼死的
Really? How?
在通風孔
In the air shaft.
可憐的傢伙 掉進9尺長的風扇
Poor soul backed into a nine-foot fan.
我發現一樣東西
I found something at the accident site,
就在離現場不遠
just a bit away from where it happened.
一個印痕 燒過的痕跡
A mark. A burn.
就像你在那女孩的低溫艙 所發現的
Rather like the one you found on the girl's cryo-tube.
聽著 我跟你同一陣線
Look. I'm on your side.
我想幫你 但我要知道這是怎麼回事
I want to help, but I need to know what's going on...
或者你覺得這是怎麼回事
or what you think is going on.
若你真的想幫我
If you really wanna help,
就幫我找一台有語音功能的電腦
find me a computer with audio capabilities...
讓我解讀飛行記錄器
so I can access this flight recorder.
這裏沒有那種設備
We don't have anything like that here.
- 那主教呢  - 主教
- Well, what about Bishop? - Bishop?
跟我一起墜機的生化人
The droid that crashed with me.
我能告訴你在哪兒
I can point you in the right direction.
不能陪你去
I can't join you.
我已經有安排了
I have a previous engagement.
馬上加滿了 Golic 別亂動
This'll top you up. Golic, don't fidget.
怎麼會這樣 根本沒有包好
What's all this shit? It's not properly wrapped.
- 他有什麼事能做好的嗎  - 吃啊
- What the hell does he ever do right? - Eat.
- 腦滿肥腸  - Golic
- He's got that down pretty good. - Golic!
- 你給Murphy點蠟燭  - 我給他點1000支
- You light a candle for Murphy. - I'll light a thousand.
他以前很特別
He was special.
從沒抱怨過我
Never complained about me once.
我喜歡他
I loved him.
他們說的是真的嗎
Is it true what they say?
他頭被絞得稀巴爛
His head split into a million pieces?
好了 誰有火柴
Okay. Who's got the matches?
- 請坐 Clemens先生  - 謝謝
- Sit down, Mr. Clemens. - Thank you.
- 糖  - 不必了
- Sugar? - Uh, no thanks.
- 奶  - 一點點 謝謝
- Milk? - Just a little, please.
謝謝 Aaron先生
Thank you, Mr. Aaron.
聽著 你這坨屎
Listen to me, you piece of shit.
如果你再耍我 小心我把你劈開
You screw with me one more time, I'll cut you in half.
對不起 我不明白你的話
I'm sorry. I don't think l understand.
7點時 我通過網絡收到公司通知
At 0700 hours, l received word from the network.
以我所知 這是這款設備
I may point out this is the first high-level communication...
接收過的最高級別通信
this installation has ever received, to my knowledge.
他們要我們好好伺候這個女人
They want this woman looked after.
- 他們把她列為最高優先級  - 為什麼
- They consider her to be very high priority. - Why?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
你為何讓她離開醫療室
But why did you let her out of the infirmary?
Murphy的意外這類事故
This accident with Murphy is what happens...
還會發生
when one of these dumb
一旦哪個混蛋勃起時亂逛的話
sons of bitches walks around with a hard-on.
我是醫生 你才是獄卒
I'm a doctor. You're the jailer.
誰不知道你的身份啊
We both know exactly what you are.
- 坐下  - 我想我最好還是出去
- Sit down. - I think it might be better if I left.
我待在你身邊就不愉快
I find you... unpleasant to be around.
是嗎 這不好嗎 仔細想想 Clemens先生
You do? Isn't that lovely? Consider this, Mr. Clemens.
你覺得我把你的齷齪歷史
How would you like me to explain your sordid history...
告訴你的新朋友怎麼樣
to your newfound friend?
當然 是給她以啟迪
For her personal edification, of course.
給我馬上坐下
Now sit the hell down.
我不喜歡你 你毫無規矩
I don't like you. You're unpredictable.
傲慢無禮 或許很危險
Insolent. Possibly dangerous.
你對什麼都懷疑
You question everything!
如果不是我需要醫務主管
If I didn't need a medical officer,
你在這兒根本待不了幾年
I wouldn't let you within light years of this operation.
- 我永遠感激  - 少說風涼話
- I'm eternally grateful. - Keep your sarcasms to yourself.
現在 有什麼要告訴我的嗎
Now, is there anything I should know?
- 想知道什麼  - 那個女人的事
- About what? - About the woman.
別玩我 Clemens
Don't play with me, Mr. Clemens.
你們基本每時每刻都在一起
You spend every second you can with her.
鬼才相信
And I have my suspicions
你這麼做全是為了治療
not all of your concerns with her are medical.
她跟你說過什麼
Has she said anything to you-
她從哪裏來 有什麼任務
anything about where she's from, what her mission is?
為什麼會在逃生艇內
What the hell she was doing in an E.E.V.?
她說他們戰隊遭遇不測
She told me she was part of a combat unit that came to grief.
其他的我想都是機密
Beyond that, I assume it's all classified.
我沒強求她說出來
I haven't pressed her for more.
- 就沒了  - 沒了
- That's all? - That's all.
- 你確定  - 確定
- You're sure? - Yes.
- 沒了 - 沒了
- Nothing more? - No.
滾出去
Get out of here.
閉嘴 他媽的騷貨
Shut up, you fuckin' bitch!
- 進去  - 閉嘴 騷婊子
- Get in there! - Shut up, you bitch!
- 喊破喉嚨也沒人  - 混蛋 放手
- Nobody's gonna hear you. - Goddamn it, let go of me!
操 不
Fuck you! No!
別動 噓
Hold still! Shh! Shh!
不 見鬼
No! Goddamn it!
沒事吧
You okay?
你個王八蛋
No! Son of a bitch!
你走吧 我要教育教育這幾位兄弟
Take off. I gotta reeducate some of the brothers.
和他們談談精神問題
We've gotta discuss some matters of the spirit.
煙
Cigarettes!
我們走吧
So let's do it.
這裏有十街區這麼大
This is like 10 city blocks.
- 有多少  - 這是第176個
- How many? - This makes 176.
吃東西小聲點
Can't you chew a little quieter?
我正在算這區段有多大
I'm trying to figure out how big this compartment is.
你這麼吵我他媽無法思考
I can't think with all this goddamn noise you're making.
- 別說髒話  - 抱歉
- You're not supposed to swear. - I'm sorry.
- 我們已經走過一圈了  - 嘿
- Now, we've encircled this entire compartment once. - Hey.
什麼
What?
那他媽是怎麼回事
What the shit is doing that?
又罵 閉嘴
Swearing. Shut up.
我罵他媽的沒關係 又不是罵上帝
It's all right to say "Shit." It ain't against God.
蠟燭怎麼就滅了
What the hell is going on with the candles?
一定是附近通風孔
Must be the wind from one of the vent shafts.
吹來的逆風
Backwash from the closest circulating unit.
要是蠟燭都被吹熄
But if all the candles go out,
我們怎麼知道自己的位置
how the hell we gonna know where we are?
只好派人回去 重新點亮
Somebody will just have to go back and relight them.
我看我去吧
I guess I'm nominated.
當心點 兄弟
Watch your step, brother.
好了 誰在開玩笑
Okay, who are the comedians?
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait!
- 快 往這走  - 救命
- Quick, grab it. Here. - Help me! Help me!
快 他媽快走
Go! Fuckin' go!
走 快點
Go, go, go! Quick! Run!
拿來
Gimme that!
把這雞巴玩意兒拿開
Get this fucking thing off me!
哦 操
Oh, fuck!
放開我
Let me go!
嘿
Hey.
啊 Ripley
Ah, Ripley.
主教 你好 感覺怎麼樣
Hi, Bishop. How you feeling?
腿疼
My legs hurt.
聽著 很抱歉
Uh, listen, I'm sorry.
沒事 我只是個至尊版的烤麵包機
It's okay. I'm just a glorified toaster.
你好嗎
How are you?
我喜歡你的新髮型
I like your new haircut.
主教 你能查飛行記錄嗎
Bishop, can you access data on the flight recorder?
沒問題
No problem.
Golic
Golic?
- 好了  - Sulaco號發生了什麼事
- I'm home. - What happened on the Sulaco?
低溫艙為何彈射出來
Why were our cryo-tubes ejected?
靜態平衡受干擾
Stasis interrupted.
低溫艙起火
Fire in cryogenic compartment.
- 重覆 低溫艙  - 發生了什麼
- Repeat. Fire in cryogenic... - What happened?
是什麼起火了 主教
What started the fire, Bishop?
能聽到我嗎
Can you hear me?
電路起火
The fire was electrical.
就在地板下面
It was in the subflooring.
脫離母艦前
Did the sensors pick up anything
傳感器有檢測到什麼東西在艦上嗎
moving around on the ship prior to separation?
這兒好暗 Ripley 我的視力大不如前
It's very dark here, Ripley. I'm not what I used to be.
告訴我 記錄儀有什麼顯示
Just tell me. Does the recorder indicate anything?
船上有異形嗎
Was there an alien on board?
有的
Yes.
它還在蘇拉可號 還是和我們一起墜機
Is it on the Sulaco or did it come with us on the E.E.V.?
它一直都和我們一起
It was with us all the way.
公司知道嗎
Does the company know?
公司知道艦上的所有事
The company knows everything that happened on the ship.
一切都輸入電腦 傳回總公司
It all goes into the computer and gets sent back to network.
他們還是要異形
And they want it.
痛啊 幫個忙 切斷電源
I hurt. Do me a favor. Disconnect me.
即使修好 也回不到以前了
I could be reworked, but I'll never be top of the line again.
我寧願變廢物
I'd rather be nothing.
你確定嗎
You're sure?
就當為我好 Ripley
Do it for me, Ripley.
不是我 不是我幹的
It wasn't me! I didn't do it!
那是 那是一條龍
It was— It was the dragon.
它吃人的腦袋
Feeds on minds. It was—
- 無法阻擋  - Boggs和Rains呢
- Nobody can stop it. - What about Boggs and Rains?
他們全像豬一樣被宰啦 不是我幹的
They got s-slaughtered like pigs. It wasn't me!
- 不是我  - 明顯整個一瘋子
- It wasn't me! - Stark raving mad.
我沒說這是誰的錯
I'm not saying it was anyone's fault,
但該把他鎖起來
but he should have been chained up.
說得是 他媽真瘋了
You called it, sir. Mad as a fucking hatter.
把他隔離
Keep him separated from the rest.
別引起恐慌
I don't want him causing a panic.
Clemens 讓這白癡鎮靜下來
Clemens, sedate this poor idiot.
我們得先弄清楚兄弟的下落
Not until we know about the brothers.
冷靜一點 告訴我
Now, now. Pull yourself together. Talk to me now.
- Boggs和Rains在哪裏  - 不是我幹的
- Now, where are Boggs and Rains? - It wasn't me!
沒用的 問不出來什麼
Hopeless. You're not gonna get anything out of him.
- 不是我  - 我們要派出一支搜尋隊
- It wasn't me. - We'll have to send out a search team.
恐怕我們得做好他們全被
I'm afraid we'll have to assume there's a very good chance...
這個畜生殺了的打算
this simple bastard has murdered them.
這你並不清楚
Now, you don't know that.
他從不騙我
He's never lied to me.
他瘋瘋癲癲 他是傻子 但是他不騙我
He's crazy, he's a fool, but he's not a liar.
他說的是真的
He's telling the truth.
我想跟他談談這條龍
I'd like to talk to him about this— this dragon.
- 就是一條龍  - 中尉 你不能跟人交談
- It was a dragon. - You're not talking to anyone, Lieutenant.
我不想聽你的觀點
I'm not interested in your opinion,
因為你根本沒搞清楚狀況
because you are not in full possession of the facts.
這個人是連環殺手
This man is a convicted multiple murderer,
手段極其殘忍
known for particularly brutal crimes.
對嗎 Dillon先生
Isn't that right, Mr. Dillon?
對 這倒沒錯
Yeah. That part's right.
那我跟你說 很重要
Then I'll talk to you. It's important.
我完成職務後
When I have finished with my official duties,
很樂意和你談 行嗎
I will be quite pleased to have a little chat, yes?
讓我先弄清楚 中尉
Let me see if I have this correct, Lieutenant.
這怪物有8英尺高
It's an eight-foot creature of some kind,
血液是強酸 坐你的太空船到達此地
with acid for blood, and it arrived on your spaceship.
它見人就殺 性情不太友善
It kills on sight and is generally unpleasant.
當然 你期望我相信你的這些話
And, of course, you expect me to accept all this on your word.
不 我什麼都不期望
No, I don't expect anything.
- 故事很精彩 Aaron先生 - 對 很精彩
- Quite a story, Mr. Aaron. - Right, sir. It's a beauty.
- 從沒聽說過這種事  - 可不是嗎
- Never heard anything quite like it, sir. - Expect not.
告訴我 中尉 你建議我們怎麼做
Tell me, Lieutenant, what would you suggest we do?
你們有哪些武器
Well, what kind of weapons have you got?
這是監獄
This is a prison.
不能讓囚犯碰武器
It's not a good idea to allow prisoners access to firearms.
那他們怎麼不殺了你
What keeps them from killing you?
恐懼 也根本逃不出去
Fear. There's no way to escape.
下一班補給船到達時
With the arrival of the next supply ship,
公司會派人消滅他們
the company would eliminate them.
這是最高安全級別的監獄
This is a maximum security prison,
你們卻什麼武器都沒有
and you have no weapons of any kind?
屠宰場有幾把菜刀
We have some carving knives in the abattoir.
飯堂也有
A few more in the mess hall.
還有一些分散的消防斧
Some fire axes scattered about the place.
沒有大威力殺傷武器
Nothing terribly formidable.
就沒了
That's all?
我們實施榮譽機制
We're on the honor system.
- 我們死定了  - 不 你死定了
- Then we're fucked. - No, you're fucked.
你將監禁在醫療室 隔離起來
Confined to the infirmary. Quarantined.
Aaron先生會護送你去
Mr. Aaron will escort you.
你在那兒最安全
I think you'll be safe from any large,
遠離野獸 不是嗎
nasty beast while you're there, right?
對 這才乖
Yes, that's a good girl.
全體到飯堂報道
Let's all report to the mess hall.
獄長Andrews召開會議
Superintendent Andrews wants a meeting.
各位 馬上來飯堂
Mess hall, right away, people.
有沒有逃離辦法 從這兒出去
Isn't there any way off of this place? Some way to escape?
沒 補給船每隔6個月才來
No. Supply ship comes every six months.
- 只有這樣  - 沒錯
- And that's it? - Mm-hmm.
可惡
Fuck.
很快就會有人來接你 據我所知
They are sending somebody to pick you up quite soon, I gather.
真的 很快是多快
Really. What's "Soon"?
不知道 以前沒有人急著來這裏
I don't know. Nobody's ever been in a hurry to get here before.
你願意說說 安德魯和你談了些什麼嗎
Do you want to tell me what you and Andrews talked about?
不
No.
你會認為我瘋了
You'll just say I'm crazy.
那有點太過分了
That's a bit uncharitable.
感覺怎麼樣
How are you feeIing?
不太好
Not so hot.
喉嚨痛
Sore throat.
胃不舒服 而且還有慪氣
Sick to my stomach. Pissed off.
在這種情況下我能理解
Well, that's understandable given the circumstances.
也許我 該給你打一劑特別的藥
Perhaps I should give you one of my special cocktails.
為什麼大家都喜歡互相指責
I don't know why everybody blames everybody for everything.
沒人是完美的 都是人啊
Nobody's perfect, only human.
世間不存在完人
There's no such thing as a perfect human.
在荒唐的世界裏
In an insane world,
一個正常人
a sane man...
必須 表現得 不正常
must... appear... insane.
很有深度 Golic 謝謝
That's very profound, Golic. Thank you.
結婚了嗎
You married?
- 我  - 你早該結婚了 生幾個孩子
- Me? - You should get married, have kids.
你這麼漂亮 我以前認識很多漂亮女孩
Pretty girl. I used to know lots of 'em back home.
她們都喜歡我
They used to like me.
很快就變心了
For a while.
你也會死的
You're gonna die too.
- 你有沒有  - 什麼
- Are you? - What?
結婚啊
Married.
怎麼了
Why?
- 好奇罷了  - 沒
- Just curious. - No.
- 你不跟我坦白嗎  - 坦白什麼
- How about leveling with me? - Could you be more specific?
我問你怎麼派到這兒來了 你沒回答
When I asked how you got assigned here, you avoided the question.
然後問你的監獄條形碼
And then when l asked about the prison I.D.
紋在你後腦勺的那個
Tattooed on the back of your head,
你又閃爍其詞
you ducked me again.
說來話長 令人傷心
It's a long, sad story...
不是一般的戲劇性
and more than a little melodramatic.
說來聽聽
Try me.
如你所願
If you insist.
學生時代結束以後
After my student years,
雖然我已經
despite the fact that I had become...
偷偷對嗎啡上癮
secretly addicted to morphine,
我仍被當做最有希望
I was considered to be most promising,
最具前程的男人
a man with a future.
我第一次住院實習時 我在急診室加班了36個小時
And during my first residency, I did a 36-hour stretch on an E.R.
所以出來後 我喝得酩酊大醉
So, I went out and I got more than a little drunk.
接著又被召回醫院
Then I got called back.
因為燃料廠的蒸汽爐爆炸
Boiler had blown on a fuel plant,
30名傷患
and there were 30 casualties.
其中11個死了
And 11 of them died.
倒不是因為意外
Not as a result of the accident...
而是因為我止痛藥計量用錯了
but because I prescribed the wrong dosage of painkiller.
我被判7年 執照降為3C
I got seven years in prison and my license reduced to a 3-C.
至少我擺脫嗎啡了
At least I got off the morphine.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我覺得自己判輕了
I think I was let off lightly.
你在這兒服刑嗎
Did you serve your time here?
我和這群烏合之眾很熟
I got to know this motley crew quite well.
所以他們不願意走時 我也留了下來
So when they stayed, I stayed.
沒別的人願意雇我
Nobody eIse would employ me.
你還相信手裏有針的我嗎
So, do you still trust me with a needle?
太壯觀了
Magnificent.
主啊 給我們力量來堅守
Give us strength, O Lord, to endure.
我們只是上帝手中
We recognize that we are
卑微的罪人
poor sinners in the hands of an angry God.
但願循環不被破壞 直到末日降臨
Let the circle be unbroken until the day. Amen.
- 阿門  - 這裏他媽怎麼回事
- Amen. - What the fuck is happening here?
怎麼他媽能出這麼多鬼事
What the fuck is this bullshit that's comin' down?
有人死了 有人強暴 有兄弟身陷困境
We got murder. We got rape. We got brothers in trouble.
我不想看到再發生什麼鬼事了
I don't want no more bullshit around here!
有問題 我們一起面對
Now, we got problems, we stand together.
謝謝 Dillon先生 好了
Yes. Thank you, Mr. Dillon. All right.
再一次 下面開始闢謠
Once again, this is rumor control.
情況如下
Here are the facts.
8時 囚犯Murphy
At 0800 hours, prisoner Murphy,
由於一時疏忽
through carelessness on his part,
在17號通風孔喪生
was found dead in vent shaft 17.
他似乎是被吸到通風風扇的
He seems to have been sucked into a ventilator fan.
大約21時
At about 2100 hours,
囚犯Golic又一次精神錯亂
prisoner Golic reappeared in a deranged state.
囚犯Boggs和Rains失蹤
Prisoners Boggs and Rains are missing.
他們倆很可能
There seems to be a good
已經遇害身亡
chance that they have met with foul play...
嫌犯為Golic
at the hands of prisoner Golic.
我們要組織一個搜救分隊
We need to organize and send out a search party.
歡迎各位踴躍報名
Volunteers will be appreciated.
這座監獄一直相安無事
I think it's fair to say that our smoothly running facility...
現在突然出現了一些問題
has suddenly developed a few problems.
只能希望我們
I can only hope we are able
接下來能振作起來
to all pull together over the next few days...
一起等待Ripley中尉的救援隊到來
until the rescue team arrives for Lieutenant Ripley.
它來了 它抓走了Clemens
It's here! It got Clemens!
別在這胡言亂語
Stop this raving at once! Stop it!
我跟你說它來了
I'm telling you, it's here!
Aaron 把這個瘋女人鎖到醫務室去
Aaron, get that foolish woman back to the infirmary!
快跑
Move it!
讓開
Out of my way!
操
Fuck!
主啊 我們感謝你
We give you thanks, O Lord.
您的憤怒已顯示 我們知道審判將至
Your wrath has come, and the time is near for us to be judged.
世界末日馬上來了
The apocalypse is upon us.
希望我們能準備好 希望您公正
Let us be ready. Let your mercy be just.
- 它太大了  - 阿門
- It was massive. - Amen!
- 還很敏捷  - 我知道 我看到了
- And fast. - I was there. I saw it.
現在他媽該怎麼辦 誰來管事
What the fuck do we do now? Who's in fucking charge?
我們得組織起來 對吧
Organize. We gotta organize, right?
對 我想我就是候補人員了
Right. Well, I guess I'm next in line.
讓85管事 天吶
85's gonna be in charge. Jesus,
- 別逗了  - 別這麼叫我
- give us a break! - Don't call me that.
聽著 我不能替代Andrews
Okay, look. There's no way I can replace Andrews.
他是個好人 我知道你們不喜歡他
He was a good man. I know you guys didn't appreciate him.
Aaron 我們現在不想聽屁話
Aaron, we don't want to hear that shit now.
你呢 妹子 你是個軍官
Hey, sister, what about you? You're an officer.
給我們展示一點領導才能吧
How about showing us a little leadership?
別管她 你管事吧
Forget fucking Shirley Temple. You take charge.
- 對  - 反正現在也是你負責
- Right. - You run things here anyway.
不可能 我不是當官的料
No fuckin' way. I'm not the officer type.
我只能管好自己
I just take care of my own.
這臭怪物想要什麼
Well, what does this fucking beast want?
這個老娘到底願不願意指揮
Is this mother gonna try for us all?
- 好吧  - 這太好了
- Yeah. - Well, ain't that sweet?
我們怎麼阻止它
So how are we gonna stop it?
- 我們沒有武器 是吧  - 對
- We have no weapons. Is that correct? - Right.
我看到過的和這只有點不一樣
I haven't seen one exactly like this before.
移動方式不一樣
Moves differently.
但其他的都怕火
But the others were afraid of fire—
別的就不怕了
not much else.
- 我們能封鎖這地方嗎  - 不可能
- Can we seal off this area? - No chance.
這監獄10平方英里
The installation's 10 miles square.
- 有600個通風管道  - 監控呢
- There's 600 air ducts running to the surface. - What about video?
我看到處都有閉路監控
I see these closed-circuit monitors everywhere.
我們能通過這個找到它
We could try to find it that way.
監控壞了很多年了 這裏的東西全是壞的
The video system hasn't worked in years. Nothing much works here.
很多高科技設備 全用不了
We got a lot of technology, no way to fix it.
- 85想說的是  - 別這麼叫我
- What 85 is trying to tell you is... - Don't call me that!
我們沒有娛樂中心 沒有氣候控制
we ain't got no entertainment center, no climate control,
沒有視頻系統 沒有監控
no video system, no surveillance,
沒冰箱 他媽連冰淇淋都沒有
no freezers, no fucking ice cream,
沒避孕套 沒女人 沒槍
no rubbers, no women, no guns.
只有他媽一堆屎
All we got here is shit!
跟她說這些有個屁用
Oh, what the hell are we even talking to her for?
那雞巴玩意兒可是她帶過來的
She's the one that brought the fucker.
為什麼我們不抓著她的頭
Why don't we just get her
塞進那雞巴牆壁裏呢
head and shove it through the fucking wall?
聽起來不錯哦
That sounds good to me.
嘿 Morse
Hey, Morse.
閉上你的鳥嘴
Why don't you shut the fuck up?
沒錯
Right.
沒錯 我們該怎麼做
Right. What are we going to do?
這是哪裏
What's this? Um,
這從飯堂通到醫療室
that leads from the mess hall to the infirmary.
是通風口
It's a ventilation shaft.
我們從這裏進去 把它逼出來
Then we go in there, flush it out.
嘿 這隧道有好幾英里長呢
Hey. Hey, look, there's miles and miles of tunnel through there.
它不會走遠的
It won't go far.
它肯定就在這片築巢
It'll nest in this area.
就在這附近
Right around here.
你怎麼知道
How do you know that?
它就像獅子
It's like a lion.
緊跟著斑馬
It sticks close to the zebras.
斑馬 哦對
Zebras? Oh, right.
這麼暗跑來跑去 你開玩笑嗎
But, look. Running around down here in the dark, are you kidding?
出了主通風孔就沒電燈的
Once you get out of this main shaft, there's no overheads.
不是有手電筒嗎
Don't we have flashlights?
是有上千個 但沒電池啊
We got thousands of 'em, but no batteries.
- 我說了 都壞了  - 火把呢
- I told you, nothing works. - Torches?
我們能生火吧
Do we have the capacity to make fire?
人類從石器時代起就有這能力
Most humans have enjoyed that privilege since the Stone Age.
沒必要這麼帶刺
No need to be sarcastic.
從沒用過 他們本來
Never been used. They were
打算扔一些廢棄核原料
gonna dump a lot of nuclear crap in there.
一直沒空 裏面空無一物
Never got around to it. It's clean as a whistle inside.
只有這一個進出口
This the only way in or out?
是的 牆壁6尺多厚 實心鋼造的
That's right. Walls are six feet thick, solid steel.
建造得真是到位
Really knew how to build these babies.
你是說我們把異形關裏面
You're saying we get something in there,
它就不可能出得來了
there's no way it can get out?
對 絕不可能
That's right. No fucking way.
原來放這兒了 這東西叫啥來著
This is where we keep it. I forget what the stuff's called.
- 圭乃特利西特林  - 我知道
- Quinitricetyline. - I knew that.
好吧 我得和Dillon一起
Right. I've got to get these
把這髹漆的工作分配好
section arrangements organized with Dillon for the paintbrush.
- 那麼 呃  - David
- So, um. - David.
- 是的 你把這些油桶準備好  - 好的 85
- Yeah. You can get these drums organized. - Right, 85.
還有 別這麼叫我
And, uh, don't call me that.
85是什麼意思
What's this "85" Thing?
他剛來的時候
Couple of us sneaked a
我們有人偷看了他的檔案
look at his personnel file the day he arrived.
這是他智商
It's his I.Q.
我以前看到過這個
I saw a drum of this stuff...
掉在灘頭的碉堡
fall into a beachhead bunker once.
炸得碼頭三個多月沒有魚群
The blast put a tug in dry dock for 17 weeks.
好東西啊
Great stuff!
讓我搞清楚
All right. Let me get this straight.
你想用火逼它出通風管
You want to burn it down and out of the pipes,
逃到這兒 把門鎖上
force it in here, slam the door...
- 然後把它困住  - 對
- and trap its ass? - Right.
你要我們 這些天生罪犯幫忙
And you want help from us y-chromo boys, huh?
你們還有其他好主意嗎
You got something better to do?
為什麼我們要冒險替你拚命呢
Why should we put our ass on the line for you?
你們已經命懸一線了
Your ass is already on the line.
唯一的問題就是
The only question is...
你們該怎麼最後一搏
what are you gonna do about it?
你看看
Look at this.
兩千個電池 只有一個能用
There's only one of these fucking batteries in 2,000 that works.
還不算最糟嘛
Hey, it could have been a lot worse.
油刷說不定還不能用呢
We might have got the paintbrush detail.
天 這玩意兒太臭了
Man, this stuff stinks.
- 這玩意臭死人了  - 那就別他媽吸氣
- This shit smells awful. - Then don't breathe the fucking fumes.
我他媽就在這個管子裏 你讓我怎麼不吸氣
I'm in a fucking pipe with it. How can I keep from breathing it!
不要深呼吸嘛
I mean, don't breathe too hard.
- 你會吸嗨的  - 那敢情好
- You'll get high. - That's good for me.
你想念醫生 是吧
So you miss Doc, right?
憑什麼這麼說呢
What makes you say that?
我猜你們親近過了
I thought you two got real close.
我猜你很喜歡偷窺
l guess you've been looking through some keyholes.
我就說
That's what l thought.
- 你還好嗎  - 沒事
- You okay? - Yeah. I'm fine.
隨你怎麼說 我看你可沒那麼好 姐妹
Whatever you say, but, uh, you don't look okay to me, sister.
真沒事
I'm fine.
我恨這地方 我恨這地方
I hate this place. I hate this place.
很明顯這裏有個什麼東西
There's definitely something in here with us.
我沒給信號 不許點火
Okay. Don't light the fire until I give the signal.
信號是這樣
This is the signal.
知道了嗎 記得住吧
Got it? Can you remember that?
該死
Shit!
他媽的怎麼不等信號
Wait for the fucking signaI!
趴下
Get down!
快點 我們得找到灑水器
Come on, come on! We gotta find the sprinklers!
快 我們得救救他們
Come on! We gotta help these guys!
快 來 來
Come on! Move! Move!
去廢料處理場 別開門
Go to the waste dump. Don't open the doors!
- 天啊  - 沒事的
- Oh, God! - It's all right.
沒事 你會沒事的 有我們在
It's all right. You're gonna be all right. We got you.
火滅了
Fire's out.
Junior Junior 去灑水器那兒 把它打開
Junior! Junior! Get those sprinklers and turn them on.
我們帶他出去
We gotta get him out of here.
來 我們帶你出去
Come on. We're walking you out.
Junior 你後面
Junior! Behind you!
開門啊
Open the door!
來 來
Come on! Come on!
來啊 來
來抓我啊 畜生
Come and get me, fucker!
即使是對那些逝去的人們
Even for those who have fallen,
現在也是慶祝的時刻
this is a time of rejoicing.
向他們的勇氣致敬
We salute their courage.
他們永垂不朽
They will live forever.
死亡並不是結束
Those that are dead are not dead.
他們啟程了
They have moved up.
他們升至天國
They have moved to a higher place.
瘋子
Crazy bastards.
Andrews稱他們為Dillon的神兵
Andrews used to call them Dillon's God Squad.
庇護他們免受傷害
Keeps 'em out of mischief.
- 你不信教嗎  - 我
- You're not the religious type. - Me?
鬼才信 我有正當工作
Shit, no. I've got a job.
聽著
Look, uh-
救援隊應該四五天後就到了
Figure the rescue team gets here in four, five days—
最多6天
six, tops.
他們一開門 拿出機關鎗轟死它
They open the door, go in there with smart guns and kill it.
- 有收到他們消息嗎  - 沒有
- What have you heard from them? - Nothing much.
只說收到訊息
We got a message received.
後來 又說你是最高優先級別
Later, we got something that said you were top priority.
他們沒給機會讓我們問話
They don't cut us in on much.
我們他媽是圖騰柱的最末端
We're the ass end of the totem pole out here.
要是他們不想殺怪物呢
What if they don't want to kill it?
- 帶回去嗎  - 對
- Take it back? - Yeah.
他們又不是瘋子 一定得殺了它
They're not lunatics, you know? Gotta kill it.
對吧
Right?
Morse 拜託 鬆開我
Morse, please, cut me loose.
不可能
No fucking way.
來啊 很痛的
Come on, man. It hurts.
對不起了
Oh, sorry.
求求你了 我什麼都沒做啊
Come on. I haven't done nothing.
- 別吵我  - 求你了 我做了什麼
- Just don't talk to me. - Please, what did I do? Please.
告訴你我會怎麼做
I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
我就坐在這兒靜靜地看著你這個傻逼
I'm gonna sit here and guard your ass like I'm supposed to.
我他媽可不想Dillon怪我
I don't need any fucking trouble with Dillon.
我就是告訴他們
All I did was tell 'em about the dragon,
那條龍殺了Boggs和Rains
what it did to Boggs and Rains.
你也看到了 我沒瞎說
I didn't lie. You saw it.
操 我看到了
Fuckin' "A" I saw it.
拜託
Oh, please.
它一進來我就死定了 我跑不了啊
If this gets in here, I'm dead. I can't run.
它進不來的 它被關起來了
It's not going to get in here. We got it trapped.
沒事的 來啊 鬆綁啊 兄弟
So what's the big deal? Come on. Let me loose, man.
- 我每次都先給你煙  - 對
- Don't I always give you cigarettes first? - Yeah.
我不是你朋友嗎
Aren't I your friend?
我愛你 Morse
I love you, Morse.
罷了罷了
Why not?
規矩點 別亂跑
But behave yourself. No fucking around...
不然我就死定了
or I'll get nothing but shit.
- 怪物在哪兒  - 廢料室
- So where they got it? - In the waste tank.
我們把它牢牢釘住了 不 關住了
We got that sucker nailed. I mean, tight.
我想再看看
Gotta see it again.
你瞎雞巴說什麼
What the fuck you talking about?
不給你煙了
No more cigarettes for you.
第一步完成了 你要說什麼
Right. We got the first part. Now what do we say?
說我們困住它了
Tell them we trapped it.
- 它叫什麼  - 異形怪物
- What do we call it? - A xenomorph.
對
Right.
怎麼拼的
How do you spell it?
等等 我們殺不掉啊
Hey, wait a minute. We can't kill it.
- 我們又沒有武器 不是嗎  - 沒錯
- We don't have any weapons, right? - Right.
看 這就是回答 屁都沒有
See? That's all they ever tell us. Treat us like shit.
- 時好時壞  - 你他媽說啥
- Off and on me now? - What the hell you talking about?
告訴我那怪獸的事
Talk to me, the beast.
你不能進去 傻逼
You can't go in there, dickhead.
那個怪物會吃掉你這傻逼的
The big motherfucker will eat you alive.
抱歉
Sorry.
對不起 對不起 對不起 對不起
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry.
告訴我接下來怎麼做
Tell me what to do next.
你是說 他們要活捉這個怪物
So, you're telling me they're coming to take this thing away?
是 他們會想盡辦法 他們不會殺它的
Yeah, they're gonna try. They don't wanna kill it.
我們得在他們來之前殺了它
We gotta figure out a way to do it before they come here.
為什麼需要我們來殺它
Why do we have to kill it?
你說公司會過來處理的
You just said the company's coming for it.
是 他們要把它帶回去
That's right. They wanna take it back.
- 用作研究武器  - 這有何不妥嗎
- Some sort of weapon. - Yeah, what's wrong with that?
他們操控不了它
They can't control it.
他們不理解危險性 它會大肆殺戮的
They don't understand. It'll kill them all.
我說了 有什麼不妥嗎
Like I said, what's wrong with that?
沒什麼不妥
Nothing's wrong with that...
只是很多無辜的人會死而已
except a lot of innocent people will die.
我以為你有宗教信仰
I thought you were a religious man.
你不明白 是吧
You don't understand, do you?
外面的世界對我們來說就如同不存在
That world out there doesn't exist for us anymore.
我們有自己的小世界
We've got our own little world out here.
不大 但只屬於我們
It ain't much, but it's ours.
其他人都滾蛋是嗎
So fuck everybody else.
是 滾蛋吧
No. Fuck them.
- Dillon  - 嗯
- Hey, Dillon? - Yeah?
有個小小的問題
Uh, Dillon, we got a teeny-weeny problem.
太棒了
Fucking great!
他媽傻逼才給他鬆綁啊
Miserable, crazy son of a bitch let him loose.
自作自受
Got what he fucking deserved.
那現在該怎麼辦
Well, now what are we gonna do?
Andrews說對了 那個豬頭就該銬起來
Andrews was right. Should've kept the shithead chained up.
你還好嗎
You okay?
去她的 那怪物
Piss on her. The fucking
現在逍遙自在 我們怎麼辦
thing's loose out there. What are we gonna do?
我剛說過了
I just said that.
就是你這傻屌讓Golic逃走的
And you're the dumb prick that let Golic out.
你這坨討嫌的大便
You miserable little shit!
得了 別吵了
Come on. Cut that shit out.
讓你那傻子好自為之
Tell your fucking bozo to shape up!
你 你覺得呢
Wh-Wh-What do you think?
我要到逃生艇去
l think I have to get to the E.E.V.
- 怎麼了  - 我得用用神經掃瞄儀
- Why? What's up? - I just have to use the neuroscanner.
- 你看起來很糟  - 管她媽看起來咋樣
- You don't look so good. - Who gives a shit how she looks?
現在該做什麼啊
What are we gonna do?
你嘴巴欠揍嗎 廢物
Want a smack in the mouth, you stupid wanker?
別吵了 別讓大家慌張
Shut the fuck up and stop causing panic!
慌張 你太他媽蠢了
Panic- You're so fucking stupid,
你字都不會寫 別跟我談慌張
you couldn't spell it. Don't talk to me about panic.
我們就該慌張 玩雞巴蛋了 這他媽誰的錯
We ought to panic! We're fucking screwed! Whose fault is that?
好了 都閉嘴
All right. Now shut up, both of you!
閉嘴
Shut up!
- 我想不出該怎麼辦  - 早料到了
- Well, I'm out of ideas! - Oh, surprise me.
- 出去怎麼樣  - 好主意
- What about outside? - Great idea.
太陽兩天後才出來 現在外面零下40度
Sun don't come up for another two days. It's 40 below zero.
救援隊還有10個小時才到 所以這辦法好極了
The rescue team's 10 hours away. So that makes a lot of sense!
太好了 你就想讓我們
Wonderful. You just want us to
待在這兒 等著那怪物來吃了我們嗎
stay here and let this thing have us for lunch!
把所有的人都聚集起來
I want you to get everybody that's still left together.
到大禮堂集合
Get 'em into the assembly hall.
好吧
Okay.
她去哪兒了
Where'd she go?
需要幫忙嗎
Need any help?
我沒想嚇你
I don't mean to scare you.
你真不該單獨亂走
You shouldn't be wandering around alone.
幫我個忙 按下按鍵 好嗎
Do me a favor and run this keyboard, will you?
好的
Okay.
- 我按哪個  - B或者C
- What do I do? - Hit "B" Or "C."
C是什麼
What's "C"?
- 顯示生命機能  - 就是它
- "Display biofunctions." - That's it.
好了 開始了 接下來呢
Okay, we're hot. Now what?
讓它跑一圈
Let it run a cycle.
很模糊啊
It's real fuzzy.
按"增強"鍵
Hit "Enhancement."
接著找
Keep looking.
我不知道怎麼看
I don't know how to read this stuff.
大出血就會有暗色塊
Hemorrhaging will show as a dark patch.
找找
Look for...
在頭骨根部有沒有細微裂痕
hairline fractures through the base of the skull.
窄窄的白線
Little white lines.
那是什麼
What is it?
好像你體內有一個
I think you've got one inside of you.
不可能吧
That's not possible.
看起來什麼樣子
What does it look like?
- 太嚇人了  - 我得看看
- Horrible. - I have to see it.
- 凍結畫面  - 你最好別看
- Freeze it. - You don't want to look at it.
凍結畫面
Freeze it!
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
好了 那怪物就在外面遊蕩
All right. The fucking thing is loose. It's out there.
救援隊帶著武器快到了
A rescue team is on its way with guns and shit.
眼下沒有哪個地方是安全的
Right now there isn't any place that's real safe.
我們待在這個大廳
But we stay here, in the assembly hall.
這兒沒有空調
This place never had any fucking air conditioning.
怪物要來 肯定是走大門
If it comes in, it's gotta be through one of these doors.
那我們就派人守衛 及時通報情況
Now we post a guard to let us know if it's coming.
同時 大家先躲好 時刻準備著
In the meantime, you lay low, be ready and stay right...
死期隨時可能到來
in case your time comes.
別編瞎話了 Dillon
Don't you start bullshitting, Dillon.
我們會像耗子一樣困在這兒
We're gonna be trapped in here like rats.
你有武器嗎 有刀嗎
You got a weapon? You got a blade?
有他媽就拿出來用啊
Then you take it out and you fucking use it!
對 所以你認為
Oh, right. So you think
我們用小刀就能捅死那雞巴怪物
we're gonna stab this motherfucker to death?
我認為個鬼 或許
No, I don't think shit! Maybe.
或許在它殺死你之前你能傷到它
Maybe you'll hurt it before it takes you out, huh?
這樣不行嗎 你們誰還有更好的主意
Isn't that something? Any of you got any better ideas?
告訴你們 在救援隊來之前 我們就等死吧
And I'll tell you, until the rescue team gets here, we're fucked!
所以你們最好準備好
So you better get prepared.
我才不留在這兒
Well, I ain't staying here.
很好 隨你便
Well, then, suit yourself.
火
Fire.
- 熔爐  - 對 把它搞到熔爐裏
- Furnace. - Yeah. Let's make it to the furnace.
我的天
Holy shit.
很好
Well, all right.
真他媽對
Fuckin' "A."
- 真他媽對  - 真他媽太對了
- Fuckin' "A." - Too fuckin' right it's right.
設定好了 你想說什麼
It's up. What do you want to say?
告訴他們這裏毒素蔓延了
Tell them the whole place has gone toxic.
開玩笑吧
Are you kidding?
這有他們就不會來了 救援隊就返回了啊
Then they won't come here. The rescue team will turn back.
- 是的 我知道  - 你在說什麼啊
- Yeah. I know. - What are you talking about?
我們唯一的希望就是他們來把它殺了
Our only hope is that they kill this fucker.
並且也能給你想想辦法
And maybe they can do something for you.
冷凍起來 或許
I don't know, freeze you-
他們能給你做手術 他們有技術啊
They can do an operation. They've got the technology.
如果異形從這兒逃走 它會毀滅一切
If this organism gets off the planet, it'll kill everything.
公司不在乎這些
The company doesn't care about that.
他們只想拿去生化武器部門 好嗎
They just want it for their bioweapons division, okay?
我們不能讓他們來
So we can't let them come here.
去你的
Fuck you.
我很遺憾你體內
Look, I'm sorry you've got
有個這東西 但是我想活命啊
this thing inside you, but I'm getting rescued.
我不是在乎這些蠢囚犯
I don't give a shit about these
我有老婆 孩子啊
stupid prisoners, but I've got a wife, I've got a kid.
- 下一班就輪到我回家了啊  - 我知道 這很難
- I'll go home on the next rotation! - I know. This is hard.
我要這麼發訊息 你他媽給我密碼
I'm gonna send this message. I need that fucking code.
抱歉 寶貝 這是機密
I'm sorry, babe. It's classified.
聽著 你個傻逼 必須這麼辦 知道嗎
Listen, you stupid little shit! This has got to be done, okay?
- 沒有其他辦法了  - 沒門兒
- There are no alternatives! - No way!
別想知道密碼 不可能
You're not getting it! No fucking way!
聽著 我跟你無冤無仇
Look, it's nothing personal.
明白嗎
Understand?
你會沒事的
I think you're okay.
謝謝
Thanks.
你有什麼主意嗎
Have you got any ideas?
它不會殺我的
It won't kill me.
我懷著皇后
I'm carrying the new queen.
它不會扼殺自己的未來
It won't kill its future.
你真認為怪物這麼聰明
You really wanna bet this thing's that smart?
我會去找它 看它到底有多聰明
Maybe I'll go find it. See how smart it is.
- 你要去找它  - 對
- You're gonna go and look for it? - Yeah.
我大概知道它在哪兒
I have a pretty good idea of where it is.
它就在下面 在地下室
It's just down there... in the basement.
這整個地方就是地下室
This whole place is a basement.
這是比喻 你來嗎
It's a metaphor. Wanna come?
操
Fuck me.
我需要你的時候你在哪裏
Where are you when I need you?
別害怕
Don't be afraid.
我也是家族成員啊
I'm part of the family.
你闖入我生活這麼久
You've been in my life so long,
我都不記得其他事了
I can't remember anything else.
現在幫個忙吧
Now do something for me.
很簡單
It's easy.
只要
Just-
只要順從你的天性
Just do what you do.
- 它不殺我  - 你在這兒幹什麼
- It won't kill me. - What are you doing out here?
你應該躺著休息
You're supposed to be laying low.
我體內也有一隻
I have one inside of me.
大的那只不願意殺死同類
Big one won't kill its own.
- 你在說什麼  - 我剛遇見它了
- What are you talking about? - I just saw it,
一小時前
an hour ago.
我就站在它旁邊
I stood right next to it.
本來我就是午飯 但它就是不碰我
I could've been lunch, but it wouldn't touch me.
它跑了
It ran away.
它知道我懷著種族的未來
It knows I'm carrying its future.
胡扯 你怎麼知道你體內也有
Aw, bullshit. How do you know that thing's inside you?
我看到了 在斷層掃瞄圖上
I saw it... on the CAT scan.
是個皇后 專門產卵的
It's a queen- an egg layer.
它會生出上千個這種怪物的
It can make thousands more like the one we've got here.
聽起來還是胡說八道
Still sounds like bullshit to me.
如果在你體內 它是怎麼進去的
If that thing's inside you, how'd it get there?
不知道
I don't know.
在我深度睡眠的時候吧
When I was in hypersleep, l guess.
我被侵犯了
I was violated.
現在我成了准媽媽
Now I get to be the mother.
我沒有多少時間了
I don't have much time,
也沒法做該做的事
and I can't do what I should.
我需要你幫助我
I need you to help me.
我要你殺了我
I need you to kill me.
- 你他媽在說什麼  - 反正我也死定了
- What the fuck are you talking about? - I'm dead anyway.
我活不了的
I can't survive it.
但我體內的怪物能繁殖上千個後代
But the one inside of me can generate thousands more,
整個宇宙都難逃浩劫
can wipe out the whole universe.
它必須死
It has to die.
所以必須殺了我
So somebody's gotta kill me.
你辦得到嗎
Are you up to it?
這你不用擔心
You don't have to worry about that.
不用說悼詞
No speeches.
也不用祈禱
No prayers.
- 怎麼了  - 我不喜歡認輸
- What's going on? - I don't like losing a fight.
對任何人或任何東西
Not to nobody, not to nothing.
操 那個該死的怪物殺了我一半兄弟
Fuck. That damn thing out there has already killed half my men,
另一半也嚇得屁滾尿流
got the other half scared shitless.
只要它還活著 姐妹
As long as it's alive, sister,
你就救不了全宇宙
you're not gonna save any universe.
你答應了要殺我的
You said you were gonna kill me.
- 你他媽膽小鬼  - 我要捉住那個怪物
- You fucking coward! - I want that thing!
我要你幫我逮住它
I want to get this thing, and I need you to do it.
如果它不殺你 那說不定對我們有利
And if it won't kill you, then maybe that helps us fight it.
否則 操你媽的
Otherwise, fuck you!
自己動手吧
Go kill yourself.
Dillon
Dillon.
我們先處理了那怪物
We waste this thing,
- 然後你要除掉我  - 沒問題
- then you take care of me. - No problem.
你會死得毫無知覺
Quick, easy and painless.
由你們自己決定
This is the choice.
是在這坐以待斃還是奮戰到死
You die sitting here on your ass, or you die out there.
至少我們該試試 讓它好看
At least we take a shot. We owe it one.
它把我們害死了 應該來個以牙還牙
It's fucked us up. Maybe we can get even for the others.
- 你們想怎麼做  - 你在胡扯什麼
- Now how do you want it? - What the fuck are you talking about?
我說殺了那個傻逼怪物
I'm talkin' about killing that big motherfucker.
別急 別急 救援隊就要來了
Hold it, hold it. The rescue team's on its way.
我們只要等著就好
We could just sit this out.
- 救援隊來幹嘛  - 救我們啊
- Rescue team for whom? - For us.
他們只想要怪物 你知道的
They just want the beast. You know that.
我才不管他們要什麼
I don't give a damn what they want.
他們又不會把我們一個個幹掉的
They're not gonna pick us off one by one, are they?
那可不一定
I wouldn't be so sure.
拜託 他們就是來接我們回去的
Come on. They're gonna take us home.
他們不會帶我們回去的
They're not gonna take us home.
但我們也不必出去拚命啊
Still doesn't mean we should go out and fight it.
天吶 都消停會兒好嗎
Jesus Christ! Give us a break!
你們他媽全瘋了
You guys have got to be fucking nuts!
我有老婆 有孩子啊
Look, I've got a wife and a kid.
沒人鳥你 85
Nobody gives a shit about you, 85.
你不是我們成員 你不信教
You're not one of us. You're not a believer.
- 你他媽是個公司走狗  - 好吧
- You're a fucking company man! - Yeah, okay.
好 我是公司員工 我他媽又不是囚犯
Okay, I'm a company man and not a fucking criminal.
你們一直嘲笑我智商
You keep telling me how dumb I am.
起碼我比你們聰明 你們一輩子關在這裏
Well, I'm smart enough not to have a life sentence on this rock!
- 操你媽  - 滾蛋去 85
- Fuck you! - Piss off, 85!
起碼我比你們聰明
Yeah, and l'm smart enough to wait for
知道等著武器來了再投入戰鬥
some firepower to show up before we fight this thing!
對吧 Morse
Right, Morse?
對 好了 你就乖乖坐在這兒 沒問題
Right. Okay. Just sit here on your asses. Fine.
我也乖乖坐在這兒怎麼樣
How about if I sit here on my ass?
沒問題 哦 我忘了
No problem. Oh, I forgot.
你和上帝商量過
You're the guy that's made a deal with God...
你要獲得永生是吧
to live forever, huh?
你們其餘這群慫貨也坐著吧
And all the rest of you pussies can sit it out too.
我和她會負責戰鬥
Me and her'll do all the fighting.
好吧 我也想殺死它
Okay. But I want the same thing as you.
我想看著它死 我也恨它 它也殺了我兄弟
I want to see it dead. I hate the fucker! It killed my mates too!
但他媽為什麼不等到
Why the fuck can't we wait
公司的人來了再拿著槍去幹它呢
for the company and have some guns on our side?
- 怎麼他媽就非得急著去送死呢  - 對
- Why do we have to go on some fucking suicide run? - Right.
因為公司不會殺它的
Because they won't kill it.
他們可能會殺了你們封鎖消息
They might kill you just for having seen it.
但絕不會殺它
But they're not gonna kill it.
太扯了 簡直是滿嘴狗屎 他們不可能會殺我們啊
That is crazy! That is horseshit! They will not kill us!
當他們一聽到異形
When they first heard about this thing,
就說 必要時可犧牲船員
it was "Crew expendable."
接下來派去的海軍陸戰隊 也說可以犧牲
The next time they sent in marines. They were expendable too.
憑什麼你就覺得
What makes you think
他們會在乎你們這幫
they're gonna care about a bunch of lifers...
在外太空尋求上帝的囚犯呢
who found God at the ass end of space?
難道你們天真以為
You really think they're going to let you...
他們會讓你們打亂他們的計劃
interfere with their plans for this thing?
他們認為我們是敗類啊
They think we're- we're crud.
他們也壓根不會在乎你們朋友的
And they don't give a fuck about one friend of yours...
死活
that's- that's died.
你們全都一樣
Not one.
你有什麼計劃呢
Have you got some sort of plan?
這是個鑄鉛場 是吧
This is a lead works, isn't it?
我們只要把那傻逼怪物引到模子裏
All we got to do is lure the fucking beast into the mold,
再用鉛水澆它
drown it in hot lead.
好吧 怎麼才能做到啊
All right. So how do we do that?
我們用什麼引誘它呢
Yeah. What are we gonna use for bait?
- 哦 操  - 我們早晚得死
- Oh, fuck! - We're all gonna die.
問題是什麼時候罷了
The only question is when.
這兒也和其他地方一樣好
This is as good a place as any...
是你們走向天堂的第一步
to take your first steps to heaven.
問題只是怎麼死罷了
Only question is how you check out.
你想站著死呢
Do you want it on your feet...
還是他媽跪著哀求著死去
or on your fucking knees, begging?
我可不會哀求
I ain't much for begging.
從沒有人施捨過我什麼
Nobody ever gave me nothin'.
所以我要干翻它 跟他拚命
So I say fuck that thing! Let's fight it!
操 干他去吧
Fuck it! Let's go for it!
- 搞死它  - 它如果衝過來怎麼辦
- Let's kick its fucking ass. - What if it runs at us?
這主意太棒了
That's a fucking good idea.
A隧道 1號門打開
Channel "A," Door 1 open.
這裏上次使用是什麼時候
When was the last time you used this place?
五六年前開過
We fired it up five, six years ago.
你確保活塞能用嗎
You sure the piston's gonna work?
這鬼地方什麼都不能確保
There's nothing for sure in this place.
我們把它困在這兒 你拉把手 開啟活塞
We trap it here first, then you pull the lever, start the piston.
然後活塞會把它
Then the piston's gonna
一直推到模子裏
push the motherfucker right into the mold.
然後再澆鉛水就好
Then one of the guys will pour the lead.
它就死了 遊戲結束
End of his ass. End of story.
萬一有人掉鏈子了呢
What if somebody screws it up?
那就完蛋了 只有一次機會
We're fucked. You got one chance.
只許成功 不許失敗
One shot at it. That's all.
沒時間重新再來
We'll never have time to reset it.
記住 你拉把手時
Now remember, when you pull the lever,
會有那麼幾秒鐘
for a few seconds you're gonna
你和那雞巴怪物都困在這兒
be trapped in here with that fuckin' thing.
你們不出岔子 我也不會
If you guys don't drop the ball, I won't.
它最好真的不會殺你
Well, you just better be right about that thing not wanting you.
因為它要出去 就只有那一條路
Because if it wants out, that's how it's gonna go.
通過凹室 通過你
Through that alcove, through you.
- 那你在哪兒  - 我在附近
- Where are you gonna be? - I'll be around.
- 其他人呢 他們在哪兒  - 禱告
- What about the others? Where are they? - Praying.
- 你相信天堂這套嗎  - 不知道
- You believe in this heaven shit? Eh? - I don't know.
我也是
Me neither.
操 但是還有什麼其他能信呢
Fuck it, though. What else have we got to believe in?
說得太他媽對了
Say that for fucking sure.
搞雞毛啊 是吧
What the fuck, right?
安靜 我聽不到
Silence! I can't hear-
啟動吧
Let's launch this thing!
B隧道 7號門
Channel "B," Door 7.
這他媽怎麼回事
I don't know about this shit.
- 嘿 各位 我的門壞了  - 他他媽說啥
- Hey, guys! My door ain't working! - What the fuck's he saying?
我們應該再計劃計劃
I think we'd better rethink this thing!
有人聽到什麼異常嗎
Did anybody hear anything?
來啊 來追我啊 你個畜生
Come on! Come and get me, you fucker!
它在追我
It's behind me!
- 開始了  - 還在追
- It's starting. - Still behind me!
在B隧道
It's in Channel "B"!
還在追 快關門
Still coming! Shut the doors!
一定朝A隧道去了
Must be heading over to Channel "A"!
這怪物被完全激怒了
This thing is really pissed off!
- 你剛說B嗎  - 不 E
- Did you say "B"? - No, "E"!
- 但你讓我們待著  - 快他媽跑
- But you said we should stay here! - Move your fucking ass!
Morse
Morse?
Kevin
Kevin!
我找到Vincent了
I think I found Vincent!
呦吼 狗東西
Yoo-hoo! Hey, fuckface!
來抓我啊 你能跑多快
Come and get me! Take your best shot!
Kevin 你在哪兒
Kevin, where are you?
A隧道 七號門關閉
A-7 closed.
打開東翼 B7號門安全
Open the east wing. Door B-7 safe!
- 沒事吧 - 沒事 所有人 去E
- You cool? - Yeah! Okay. Over to "E," Everybody!
- E隧道他媽在哪兒  - 這邊
- Where the fuck is "E"? - This way!
Troy Troy 幫他們
Troy. Troy? Troy, help 'em!
我怎麼到這兒了
How did I get here?
他們他媽是去哪兒 怎麼不按計劃
Where the hell are they going? What about the plan?
- 你免疫了 他們沒有  - 那該怎麼辦
- Look, you're immune, they're not. - So what are we doing?
- 隨機應變  - 我們隨機應變
- Improvising! - We're improvising.
太好了
Great.
這兒 這兒 咪咪 咪咪
Here. Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
這兒 咪咪
Here, kitty, kitty.
哦 天吶
Oh, my God.
你個畜生
Oh, my- You bastard!
來了 它來了 Dillon 天吶 來了
It's coming! It's coming, Dillon! Geez, it's coming!
追著我們來了 快按計劃關門
It's comin' after us! Shut the fucking doors! That was the plan!
天吶 在天花板上
Geez, it's on the fucking ceiling!
Dillon 有人嗎 這不是演習
Dillon! Anybody! This is not a drilI!
Kevin Gregor
Kevin! Gregor!
你們他媽在哪兒
Where the fuck are you?
我回到A隧道了
Now I'm back in "A"!
快 快 快
Shut. Come on.
F隧道 3號門關閉
Door 3, "F" Channel closed!
希望如此
I hope.
操
Fuck!
- 你他媽在幹嘛  - 怎麼了
- What the fuck are you doing? - What?
- 別這樣拿 這樣拿  - 搞毛啊
- Don't hold it like that. Hold it like this. - What the fuck-
你會誤傷人的 傻逼
You'll fucking kill someone, you fucking moron! Ow!
Morse Kevin
Morse! Kevin!
Gregor
Gregor!
他們只要沿著迴廊跑就好了啊
All they have to do is run down the damn corridor.
待在這兒
Stay here.
它到底在哪兒
Where the hell is it?
來了 天吶
It's coming. Aw, Jesus!
別 別動活塞
No! Don't start the piston!
別 我們得先困住它
No! We have to trap it! No!
別 你在做什麼 它跑了
No! What are you doing? It's gone! No! No.
它跑了
It's gone.
知道嗎
Okay?
好的
Okay.
這他媽
What the heck?
好吧
All right!
Kevin 別掙扎
Kevin! Don't struggle!
別動 不 別掙扎
Don't move! No! Don't struggle!
快 快 Kevin
Come on. Come on, Kevin. Come on!
來 來 來啊
Come on! Come on! Come on.
- 關門  - 它來了
- The doors. - It's coming!
準備活塞
Take the piston!
好了 沒事了
I got ya. It's all right.
沒事了 沒事了
It's okay. I got ya. It's okay.
沒事了 Kevin
It's all right, Kevin.
Kevin
Kevin!
Kevin.
別管他了
Leave him.
我們走 他死了 引它進來
Leave him. He's dead. Lure it in.
可惡 有多久
Shit. How much time?
不確定 四五分鐘吧
I'm not sure. Four or five minutes.
我們得把它弄進來
But we've got to get it back
活塞把這兒封了就晚了
in here before the piston seals this place off.
快 動作快點
Now, let's move it!
- 幫幫我  - Jude
- Help me! - Jude!
Dillon 救我 Dillon
Dillon! Help me, Dillon!
它朝我來了
It's coming at me!
別往後看 Jude 你他媽撒開腿跑
Don't look back, Jude! Run as fast as you fucking can!
救我
Help me!
天 快 救我
God! Please! Help!
C隧道 3號門關閉
Channel "C," Door 3 closed.
老天啊 你們終於來了
Jesus Christ! Thank God you're here.
獄吏Aaron 長官 137512
Warder Aaron, sir. 1 -3-7-5-1 -2.
- 我們沒剩幾個了 長官  - Ripley中尉在哪兒
- Not many of us left, sir. - Where is Lieutenant Ripley?
- 她還活著嗎  - 她肯定在熔爐那裏
- Is she still alive? - If she's alive, she's in the furnace.
她和怪獸在鑄鉛場
She's in the lead works with the beast.
她不等你們
Wouldn't wait.
老天 傻逼 嚇尿我了
Jesus Christ. You fucker. Scared me shitless!
我還以為是那雞巴怪物呢 混蛋
I thought you were the fucking beast. You fuck!
笨蛋
Wanker!
快 來啊 蠢貨
Move. Come on, you bastard!
來啊 出來啊
Come on! Come on, get out of there!
來這兒啊
Come here!
Ripley 沒時間了
Ripley, we're running out of time!
Ripley 你在哪兒
Ripley, where are you? -
不
No!
來 出來啊
Come on. Get out of there!
- 你他媽有病啊  - 不 不
- What the fuck is wrong with you? - No! No!
別理它 算了
Let it go! Let it go!
- 好的 奏效了  - 快喊
- Yes! It's working! - Scream!
到活塞 快喊 讓它跟著來
To the piston! Scream! Let it follow us.
快來 把它引到活塞前面
Come on! We got to get it in front of the piston.
進去 它跟來了
Get back there. It's following us!
傻逼 來啊 來抓我啊
Motherfucker! Come on! Come and get us!
來
Come on!
到門那兒去 關上
Up to the door! Close it!
來啊 傻逼 來啊
Come on, motherfucker! Come on.
快 關門
Come on! Get the door!
- 關門  - Morse
- Get the door! - Morse!
現在 關上
Now! Shut it!
關上 Morse
Shut it, Morse!
Morse 關門啊
Morse, shut that door!
- 馬上  - 你他媽關門啊
- Now! - Shut the fucking door!
我去倒熱鉛
I'm going for the lead!
- 快  - 你呢
- Go! Now! - What about you?
- 我留下  - 扯淡
- O'm staying. - Bullshit!
等會兒有10噸的熱鉛下來
There's gonna be 10 tons of hot lead in there!
- 我說了 我想死  - 說好了的
- I keep telling you, I want to die! - We got a deal!
記得嗎 它先死 然後你再死
Remember? It dies first, then you!
我不會撇下你不管的 現在 快
I'm not gonna move without you! Now get going!
- Dillon  - 我拖住它
- Dillon! - I've got to hold it here.
- 我呢  - 上帝保佑你 姐妹
- What about me? - God will take care of you now, sister!
不
No!
倒鉛
Pour the lead.
操
Fuck you.
快 倒啊 Ripley 快
Go on! Pour it, Ripley! Go on! Damn it!
把鉛倒下來
Pour that lead, Ripley! Pour it now!
來啊 你就這點本事
Come on! Come on! That's all you've got?
傻逼 你就這麼打架嗎
Is that all that you fight, motherfucker! Come on!
Morse 在這兒
Morse! Morse, over here!
- Ripley  - 倒鉛
- Ripley! - Pour the lead!
倒鉛
Pour the lead!
倒啊
Pour it!
我討厭蟲子
I hate bugs!
Ripley 它很燙的
Ripley! It's burning hot!
開灑水器
Hit the sprinklers!
給它來個水淬
Douse the fucker!
中了
Gotcha!
好耶
Yes!
- 不要再過來了  - 他們是來幫忙的
- Don't come any closer. - Wait. They're here to help.
你別動
Stay where you are!
- Ripley  - 主教
- Ripley. - Bishop.
- 我是來幫你的  - 別扯了
- I'm here to help you. - No more bullshit.
我感覺到它在動
I just felt it move.
- 你知道我是誰嗎  - 你是生化人
- You know who I am? - You're a droid.
和主教型號一樣 公司派來的
Same model as Bishop. Sent by the fucking company.
不 我不是生化人主教
No. I'm not the Bishop android.
他是我設計的
I designed it.
我是人類
I'm very human.
公司派了個熟悉的面孔給你
The company sent me here to show you a friendly face,
以此展示你對我們的重要性
to demonstrate how important you are to us,
對我也是
to me.
你只想把它帶回去
You just want to take it back.
我們想殺了它 然後帶你回家
We want to kill it and take you home.
- 胡扯  - 你錯了 我們就是來幫忙的
- Bullshit. - You're wrong. We want to help.
怎麼個幫法
What does that mean?
- 我們把它取出來  - 然後留它活口
- We're gonna take that out of you. - And keep it.
不能讓它活著 人類的一切都將面臨威脅
Can't allow it to live. Everything we know would be in jeopardy.
你不想帶它回去嗎
You don't want to take it back?
Ripley 時間緊急 這個惡魔交給我們處理
Ripley, time is important. Let us deal with the malignancy.
救援艦上有手術台
We've got a surgical bay set up on the rescue ship.
來吧 很快的
Come with me. It's very quick.
無痛 只有幾刀 兩小時就好
Painless. A couple of incisions. You'll be out for two hours.
然後一切都結束了
And then it's over.
你仍可以正常生活 生兒育女
You still can have a life, children-
並且 它肯定會死
And most important, you'll know it's dead.
讓我幫你
Let me help you.
憑什麼讓我信你
What guarantee do l have...
你們取出來 憑什麼相信你們會殺了它
once you've taken it out, you'll destroy it?
你得信任我
You have to trust me.
拜託了 相信我
Please? Trust me?
不
No.
這有什麼用
What's this gonna achieve?
- 停下  - 哦 天吶
- Stop! - Ow! Oh, Jesus!
Morse
Morse.
- 你願意幫我嗎  - 你要我怎麼做
- Will you help me? - What do you want me to do?
剛誤會了 我們沒必要這樣
It was a mistake! There was no need for any of it!
傻逼生化人
Fucking android!
我不是生化人
I'm not a droid!
Ripley 想想我們能從它身上學到什麼
Ripley, think of all we could learn from it.
這機會百年一遇啊
It's the chance of a lifetime!
你得讓我留下它 它是個偉大的標本
You must let me have it! It's a magnificent specimen!
天啊
Oh, Jesus!
別拍了
No pictures!
你瘋了
You're crazy.
你在做什麼
What are you doing?
不
No!
- 快走 別磨磨唧唧  - 去你的
- Come on, you. Get going. - Oh, fuck you!
Ash Dallas船長死了
Ash, Captain Dallas are dead.
貨物和飛船全部被毀
Cargo and ship destroyed.
我將在6周後抵達邊界
I should reach the frontier in about six weeks.
幸運的話 會有人收到我的訊息的
With a little luck, the network will pick me up.
我是Ripley
This is Ripley,
Nostromo的唯一倖存者 通話結束
last survivor of the Nostromo, signing off.